Guide to the Coca Crystal Video Recordings and Papers MSS.468
Fales Library and Special Collections
Coca Crystal Video Recordings and Papers
1976-2012
Fales Library and Special Collections
Crystal, Coca
MSS.468
35 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 1 half manuscript box, 33 record cartons, and 1 flat box
326 U-matic
31 VHS
79 Half_Inch_Video_Reel
Coca Crystal (1947-2016), born Jacquline Diamond, was a journalist, television personality, and political activist. Beginning in 1969, Diamond contributed to the East Village Other under the pen name Coca Crystal, writing about counterculture politics with a strong focus on women's issues. From 1977 until 1995, she created and hosted the cable-access variety television program The Coca Crystal Show: If I Can't Dance, You Can Keep Your Revolution, which featured political commentary, music, guest interviews, and audience call-ins. This collection consists of issues of the East Village Other and other underground publications, recordings of The Coca Crystal Show on 1/2 inch open reel, U-matic, and VHS video tapes, and biographical and promotional materials about Coca Crystal and her show.
Content Description
This collection consists of materials created and collected by Coca Crystal documenting her career as a journalist and television personality. Included in the collection are issues of the East Village Other, Overthrow Magazine, and other underground publications that Crystal and her contemporaries contributed to; recordings of her cable-access telivision show, The Coca Crystal Show: If I Can't Dance, You Can Keep Your Revolution, on 1/2 inch open reel, U-matic, and VHS video tapes; biographical and promotional video tapes about Coca Crystal and her show; a Certificate of Appreciation awarded to Crystal by the Metropolitan Playhouse in 2012; and recordings of Polar Bear News, created by a friend of Crystal's, on U-matic and VHS video tapes.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into four series:
Series I. Written Works includes issues of the East Village Other, Overthrow Magazine, and other underground publications that Coca Crystal and her contemporaries contributed to. This series is arranged chronologically.
Series II. The Coca Crystal Show: If I Can't Dance, You Can Keep Your Revolution includes recordings of Coca Crystal's cable-access telivision show on 1/2 inch open reel, U-matic, and VHS video tapes. This series is arranged chronologically.
Series III. Biographical and Promotional Materials includes telivision appearances and interviews by Coca Crystal, as well as recordings of events that she went to, on U-matic and VHS video tapes. It also includes a Certificate of Appreciation awarded to Cyrstal by the Metropolitan Playhouse in 2012. This series is arranged alphabetically.
Series IV. Polar Bear News includes recordings of the news segment, which was created by a friend of Coca Crystal.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact special.collections@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Jill Diamond, sister of Coca Crystal (Jackie Diamond), in December 2016; the accession number associated with this gift is 2016.058.
Biographical Note
Coca Crystal (1947-2016), born Jacquline "Jackie" Diamond, was a journalist, television personality, and political activist. Beginning in 1969, Diamond contributed to the East Village Other under the pen name Coca Crystal, writing about counterculture and politics with a strong focus on women's issues. In 1975, Diamond adopted her sister's young son, Gustav "Gus" Che Finkelstein.
In 1977, she created the cable-access variety television program The Coca Crystal Show: If I Can't Dance, You Can Keep Your Revolution, which ran until 1995. The Coca Crystal Show featured political commentary, music, guest interviews, and audience call-ins. Some of the show's sketches included Sinsemilla Stret: The World's Only Consumer Video Pot Report, Radical Walking Tours with Bruce Kayton, Newt News, No Nukes, and Archive Tapes. The show usually began with Coca Crystal lighting a joint and ended with her and the show's guests dancing together. Regular contributers included photojournalist Charlie Frick, music journalist Leslie Kandell, Pam Lloyd, poet Vincent Titus, journalist Nancy Borman, Mike Chance, Bud Bogart, Lannes Kenfield, poet Tuli Kupferberg, journalist Jim Buckley, talent coordinator Maureen Ivice, Marty Brown, activist Bruce Kayton, environmental educator Steve "Wildman" Brill, director Ed Caraballo, Beanie the dog, and Judith Malina, Steve Ben Israel, and Jasmine Vegas of "The Living Theatre." Gus Finkelstein also made several appearances on the show and was often referred to as the "executive producer."
In 2012, the Metropolitan Playhouse awarded a Certificate of Appreciation to Coca Crystal. In 2013, Danielle Quisenberry portrayed Crystal in a one-woman show performed for the East Village Theater Festival at the Metropolitan Playhouse.
Coca Crystal passed away in 2016, 10 years after being diagnosed with lung cancer.
Public-access television.; Variety shows (Television programs); Journalists -- New York (State) -- New York.; Television journalists.; Counterculture -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Underground newspapers -- United States; Kupferberg, Tuli; Harry, Debbie; Living Theatre (New York, N.Y.); Hoffman, Abbie; Glass, Philip
- Series I. Written Works, 1970-1981
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. Written Works includes issues of the East Village Other, Overthrow Magazine, and other underground publications that Coca Crystal and her contemporaries contributed to.
  - The East Village Other Volume 5, Issues No. 12-21, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - The East Village Other Volume 5, Issues No. 23-47, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - The East Village Other Volume 6, Issues No. 1-14, 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - The East Village Other Volume 6, Issues No. 29-36, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - The East Village Other Volume 6, Issues No. 37-45, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - The East Village Other Volume 7, Issue No. 2, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - N.Y. Daily Planet Volume 1, No. 4, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - High Times, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Overthrow Magazine, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Overthrow Magazine, 1980 (Box 34, Box 8)
  - Alternative Media Magazine, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series II. The Coca Crystal Show: If I Can't Dance, You Can Keep Your Revolution, 1977-1995
  Series II. The Coca Crystal Show: If I Can't Dance, You Can Keep Your Revolution, includes recordings of Coca Crystal's cable-access telivision show on 1/2 inch open reel, U-matic, and VHS video tapes. When possible, each recording's title describes that episode's main guests.
  - Production Cue Sheets, 1977-1995; cuid29989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Amy Melnick of the Wall Street Action Coalition, Steve Ben Israel, circa 1977-1980; cuid29680 (Box 37, Half inch video reel 468_066)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Preservation Note: Sound levels jump up and down throughout tape.
  - Aircheck - Rex Weiner, Deanne Stillman, Sam Rowan, Boo Patton, September 21, 1977; cuid29618 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_001)
  - Tuli Kupferberg, The Bowery Strings, October 19, 1977; cuid29619 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_002, 468_003)
  - Pam Lloyd, Virginia Cavarizzuto, Warren Shakespeare, October 26, 1977; cuid29620 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_004)
  - Commander Video, Pam Lloyd, November 2, 1977; cuid29621 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_005)
  - Virginia Cavarizzuto, Allen Gitler, Pam Lloyd, November 7, 1977; cuid29622 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_006)
  - Live from E.T.C., November 9, 1977; cuid29623 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_007)
  - Commander Video, Dr. John, Classical Music Trio, November 23, 1977; cuid29624 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_008)
  - Pam Lloyd, December 14, 1977; cuid29625 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_009)
  - Pam Lloyd, Leslie Kandell, Captain Crunch, January 4, 1978; cuid29626 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_010)
  - Nancy Borman, January 11, 1978; cuid29627 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_011, 468_012)
  - Pam Lloyd, Jason Holograms, Vincent Titus, January 18, 1978; cuid29628 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_013)
  - Commander Video, January 25, 1978; cuid29629 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_014)
  - Chris Chadwick, February 1, 1978; cuid29630 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_016)
  - Nancy Borman, Leslie Kandell, Pot Poll, February 8, 1978; cuid29601 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_015)
  - Vincent Titus, Dave Dellinger, Bobby Bellato, Leslie Candell, Pam Lloyd, February 15, 1978; cuid29631 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_017)
  - The Bard, Winslow Peck, Sam Rohn, Vincent Titus, February 22, 1978; cuid29632 (Box 2, Half inch video reel 468_018)
  - Ken Weiner, Leslie Kandell, Vincent Titus, Robert Bellato, March 1, 1978; cuid29633 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_019)
  - Claudette Furlong, Vincent Titus, Leslie Kandell, Pam Lloyd, Charlie Frick, March 8, 1978; cuid29634 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_020)
  - Deanne Stillman, Charlie Frick, Pam Lloyd, March 15, 1978; cuid29635 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_021)
  - Jim Mason, March 22, 1978; cuid29636 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_022)
  - Tom Leykis, Sandy Levitt, March 29, 1978; cuid29637 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_023)
  - Art Spiegelman, Allen Gittler, Cindy and Her Cello, April 12, 1978; cuid29638 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_024)
  - Commander Video, Leslie Kandell, April 26, 1978; cuid29639 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_025)
  - Belly Dancers, May 3, 1978; cuid29640 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_026)
  - The Philadelphia Sound, May 10, 1978; cuid29641 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_027)
  - Glenn Tepper, David Klein and Beenie, May 24, 1978; cuid29642 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_028)
  - Unlabeled, June 7, 1978; cuid29643 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_029)
  - Bob Rudnick, Bob Patton, June 14, 1978; cuid29644 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_030)
  - Murray Rosenbliss, Win Magazine, Suni Paz, June 21, 1978; cuid29645 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_031)
  - Tuli Kupferberg, June 29, 1978; cuid29646 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_032)
  - David Klein and Beenie, September 27, 1978; cuid29647 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_033)
  - Master, October 10-11, 1978; cuid29648 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_034)
  - Glenn O'Brien, October 18, 1978; cuid29649 (Box 37, Half inch video reel 468_035)
    Preservation Note: Levels vary greatly throughout tape. Video breakup at beginning of tape leads into black then into program.
  - Frisbee Freaks, Mike Foldis, October 25, 1978; cuid29650 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_036)
  - Coca, Vincent, Bobby Joe, Lily, Leslie, Pam, November 1, 1978; cuid29651 (Box 3, Half inch video reel 468_037)
  - Steve Ben Israel, November 8, 1978; cuid29652 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_038)
  - David Klein and Beenie, Clark Beaner, Sam Rohn, Lola La Plume, November 22, 1978; cuid29653 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_039)
  - Tuli Kupferberg, November 29, 1978; cuid29654 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_040)
  - Steve Ben Israel, December 6, 1978; cuid29655 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_041)
  - Nancy Borman, Les Nikolettes, December 20, 1978; cuid29656 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_042)
  - Winslow Peek, December 26, 1978; cuid29657 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_043)
  - Aron Kay, Leslie and Coca, January 10, 1979; cuid29658 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_044)
  - Nancy Borman, January 17, 1979; cuid29659 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_045)
  - Dan and Bobby Jo, January 24, 1979; cuid29660 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_046)
  - Steve Ben Israel, January 31, 1979; cuid29661 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_047)
  - Unlabeled, February 14, 1979; cuid29662 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_048)
  - Unlabeled, February 21, 1979; cuid29663 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_049)
  - Jim Mason, February 28, 1979; cuid29664 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_050)
  - Dana Beal, March 28, 1979; cuid29665 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_051)
  - Unlabeled, April 4, 1979; cuid29666 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_052)
  - George Buss, Shad Alliance, April 11, 1979; cuid29667 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_053)
  - Eric Williams, April 18, 1979; cuid29668 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_054)
  - Paulette Nenner, Karen Zimmerman, Manual Lutgenhurst, April 25, 1979; cuid29685 (Box 7, U-matic 468_071)
    Duration: 60 minutes
  - Unlabeled, April 25, 1979; cuid29669 (Box 4, Half inch video reel 468_055)
  - George Bliss, Vincent singing with David Klein, Steve Ben Israel, May 2, 1979; cuid29670 (Box 5, Half inch video reel 468_056)
  - Beautiful Foot Contest, Kentucky Hemp Guild, Dr. Drizzle, May 9, 1979; cuid29671 (Box 5, Half inch video reel 468_057)
  - Steve Ben Israel, May 16, 1979; cuid29672 (Box 5, Half inch video reel 468_058)
  - Bill Means, AIM, Black Hills Alliance, May 23, 1979; cuid29673 (Box 5, Half inch video reel 468_059)
  - Dr. Michio Kaku, June 6, 1979; cuid29674 (Box 5, Half inch video reel 468_060)
  - Aaron Kay, June 13, 1979; cuid29675 (Box 5, Half inch video reel 468_061)
  - Nancy Borman, Conversation with the Radical Lesbian Feminist Terrorist Comedy Group, May 20, 1979; cuid29676 (Box 5, Half inch video reel 468_062)
    Note on videotape case: "Produced by Coca Crystal. Also starring Pam with Sinsemilla Street, the world's only consumer video pot report. With a poem by Vincent Titus. Conversation with the Radical Lesbian Feminist Terrorist Comedy Group. The Mad Consumer Report with Leslie Kandell. Artifacts of the future, Main Guest: Nancy Borman. About Village Voice article concerning Gloria Steinem and the CIA, Random House censoring a Redstockings book. Phone calls wiht Coca. Kids survey. Dope of the week - Thai Stick. Ending with wild dancing."
  - Steve Ben Israel, George Bliss on Shoreham, June 27, 1979; cuid29677 (Box 5, Half inch video reel 468_063)
  - Debbie Harry, Chris Stein of Blondie, September 26, 1979; cuid29678 (Box 7, U-matic 468_064)
  - Marpessa Dawn, Seabrook Occupiers, Tom Brim, Tim Hughes, October 3, 1979; cuid29679 (Box 5, Half inch video reel 468_065)
  - Unlabeled, November 14, 1979; cuid29682 (Box 5, Half inch video reel 468_068)
  - Aaron Kay, Steve Ben Israel, Tape of "Him or Me," Leslie & Kids Orthodontia Game, December 5, 1979; cuid29683 (Box 5, Half inch video reel 468_069)
  - John Wilcock, December 12, 1979; cuid29681 (Box 5, Half inch video reel 468_067)
  - Unlabeled, December 12, 1979; cuid29684 (Box 5, Half inch video reel 468_070)
  - Unlabeled, January 2, 1980; cuid29696 (Box 6, Half inch video reel 468_083)
  - Mobilization to Stop the Draft, January 9, 1980; cuid29697 (Box 6, Half inch video reel 468_084)
  - Leopold Maler, Noreen Ash McKay, January 16, 1980; cuid29698 (Box 6, Half inch video reel 468_085)
  - Unlabeled, January 23, 1980; cuid29699 (Box 6, Half inch video reel 468_086)
  - Unlabeled, February 13, 1980; cuid29700 (Box 6, Half inch video reel 468_087)
  - Unlabeled, February 20, 1980; cuid29701 (Box 6, Half inch video reel 468_088)
  - Unlabeled, March 5, 1980; cuid29702 (Box 6, Half inch video reel 468_089)
  - Angie Fa, Mobilization Against the Draft, March 19, 1980; cuid29703 (Box 6, Half inch video reel 468_090)
  - Unlabeled, March 26, 1980; cuid29704 (Box 6, Half inch video reel 468_091)
  - Unlabeled, April 9, 1980; cuid29705 (Box 6, Half inch video reel 468_092)
  - Live from ETC Studios, May 14, 1980; cuid29824 (Box 16, U-matic 468_222)
    Duration: 30 minutes; Preservation note: Broken tape needed repair, no color burst.
  - Live from ETC Studios, May 28, 1980; cuid29825 (Box 16, U-matic 468_223)
    Duration: 60 minutes; Preservation note: Broken tape needed repair, no color burst, sound is intermittent
  - Dana Lobell, Women Against Pornography, June 4, 1980; cuid29686 (Box 7, U-matic 468_072)
    Duration: 60 minutes; Preservation note: This tape required incubation, and the best possible capture was transferred
  - Live from ETC, June 18, 1980; cuid29687 (Box 7, U-matic 468_073)
    Duration: 60 minutes. Preservation note: This tape required incubation.
  - A.J. Weberman - Garbologist, Youth Affairs - Secret Rocker, June 25, 1980; cuid29990 (Box 29, U-matic 468_392)
    This episode also features a Public Service Announcement with Leslie Kandell, a poem by Vincent Titus, Sinsemilla Street with Mike Chance, and answering phones with Coca Crystal.
    Duration: 30 minutes
  - Bob Singer, Pick-Up Times, July 9, 1980; cuid29688 (Box 7, U-matic 468_074)
  - Shad Alliance, Steve Ben Israel, The Great Tampon Debate, September 17, 1980; cuid29602 (Box 35, U-matic 468_075)
  - Anti-Klan Discussion, October 15, 1980; cuid29689 (Box 7, U-matic 468_076)
  - Herbal Advice from Nancy, Cultural Attache, October 22, 1980; cuid29690 (Box 7, U-matic 468_077)
  - Tuli Kupferberg, Vincent Titus, Leslie Kandell, Aaron Kay, Chris, October 29, 1980; cuid29691 (Box 7, U-matic 468_078)
    This episode features a poem by Vincent Titus, singing by Tuli Kupferberg, an announcement by Leslie Kandell, an interview with Aaron Kay, a Sensemilla Street Ganja Song by Chris [?], and Coca Crystal answering viewer calls.
  - Gabrielle Schang, November 12, 1980; cuid29603 (Box 35, U-matic 468_124)
  - The Women's Action in the Pentagon, Beanie the Singing Dog, November 19, 1980; cuid29692 (Box 7, U-matic 468_079)
  - Abbie Hoffman, December 17, 1980; cuid29693 (Box 7, U-matic 468_080)
    Duration: 55 minutes. Preservation note: This tape required incubation.
  - "New Years Eve Super Special Goodbye 80, Hello 81 TV Special!", December 31, 1980; cuid29694 (Box 7, U-matic 468_081)
    Duration: 59 minutes
  - Ralph Manis, Beanie the Singing Dog, January 28, 1981; cuid29695 (Box 7, U-matic 468_082)
  - Steve Rankin, All My Children, March 4, 1981; cuid29707 (Box 7, U-matic 468_094)
  - Patrick Kilpatrick, Nancy Boreman, Chris Young, Mike Chance, March 11, 1981; cuid29706 (Box 7, U-matic 468_093)
    This episode features a poem by Vincent Titus, Beanie the Singing Dog, Leslie Kandell, a video about the purity of wine by Patrick Kilpatrick, news with Nancy Boreman, an interview with Chris Young, and a pot poll with Mike Chance answering viewer phone calls.
  - Yippies Bombed, March 18, 1981; cuid29708 (Box 37, U-matic 468_095)
  - April Fools Edition: Rex Weiner, Mike Chance, David Klein and Beanie, April 1, 1981; cuid29709 (Box 8, U-matic 468_096)
  - Tom Hachtman, April 8, 1981; cuid29710 (Box 8, U-matic 468_097)
  - Fekner, Beanie, Chance, April 15, 1981; cuid29711 (Box 8, U-matic 468_098)
    Duration: 60 minutes. Preservation note: This tape required incubation, and the best possible capture was transferred.
  - Jim Neo, John Nesci, May 6, 1981; cuid29712 (Box 8, U-matic 468_099)
    Duration: 57 minutes
  - Tama Janowitz, May 27, 1981; cuid29713 (Box 8, U-matic 468_100)
    Duration: 56 minutes
  - John Lennon, June 10, 1981; cuid29714 (Box 8, U-matic 468_101)
    Duration: 8 minutes
  - Philip Glass, June 10, 1981; cuid29715 (Box 8, U-matic 468_102)
    Duration: 55 minutes
  - Jill Diamond, October 7, 1981; cuid29716 (Box 8, U-matic 468_103)
  - Paulette Nenner, Mary Bloom, October 14, 1981; cuid29717 (Box 8, U-matic 468_104)
    Duration: 61 minutes
  - Vincent Titus, Nancy Boreman, Renfreu, A.J. Weberman, October 21, 1981; cuid29718 (Box 8, U-matic 468_105)
    This episode features a poem with Vincent Titus, news with Nancy Boreman, A.J. Weberman, theatre with Renfreu, and a pot poll with viewer phonecalls.
  - Jango Edwards, October 28, 1981; cuid29719 (Box 8, U-matic 468_106)
  - Tiny Tim, Tom Hachtman, Isadore Fertel, Mike Chance, November 11, 1981; cuid29720 (Box 8, U-matic 468_107)
  - Jim Buckley, Vincent Titus, Nancy Boreman, Renfreu, November 18, 1981; cuid29721 (Box 8, U-matic 468_108)
    This episode features announcements by Jim Buckley, a poem by Vincent Titus, news with Nancy Boreman, and theatre with Renfreu.
  - Jim Chladek, Deeane Stillman, December 2, 1981; cuid29722 (Box 8, U-matic 468_109)
  - Opening: Washing the Sink, December 9, 1981; cuid29723 (Box 9, U-matic 468_110)
  - Christmas Special, December 23, 1981; cuid29724 (Box 9, U-matic 468_111)
  - Editta Sherman, "The Duchess of Carnegie Hall', January 6, 1982; cuid29725 (Box 9, U-matic 468_112)
  - Jill Sieden, Tom Duffy, January 13, 1982; cuid29726 (Box 9, U-matic 468_113)
  - Andy Kowl, Vincent Titus, Mike Chance, January 20, 1982; cuid29727 (Box 9, U-matic 468_114)
    This episode features special guest Andy Kowl, a poem with Vincent Titus, and Mike Chance.
  - Nick Yanni, February 17, 1982; cuid29728 (Box 9, U-matic 468_115)
  - Alan Ebert Miner of C.I.S.P.E.S., February 24, 1982; cuid29729 (Box 9, U-matic 468_116)
  - Act from Play "Basic Behavior" Featuring John Nesci, Jim Neu, SK Dunne, and Paul Garasso, March 10, 1982; cuid29730 (Box 9, U-matic 468_117, Box 29, U-matic 468_393)
    This episode also features an announcement by Jim Buckley, a poem by Vincent Titus, news with Nancy Borman and Coca, and Sinsemilla Street with special guest Allan Birnbaum.
  - Steve Ben Israel, March 3, 1982; cuid29604 (Box 35, U-matic 468_125)
  - C.I.S. PES, C.L.A.R.O., Richard Bey, March 17, 1982; cuid29736 (Box 9, U-matic 468_123, Box 10, U-matic 468_126)
  - Tuli Kupferberg, Shay Adams, March 31, 1982; cuid29738 (Box 10, U-matic 468_127)
  - Ground Zero Club: Bill LaRosa, Steve Jenkins, Adrian Stokes, April 7, 1982; cuid29739 (Box 10, U-matic 468_128)
  - Gerad Malagna, Nat Finklestein, Green Party, April 13, 1982; cuid29740 (Box 10, Vhs 468_129)
    Duration: 121 minutes
  - Herbal Tracers, Music by Bob Patton, May 5, 1982; cuid29741 (Box 10, U-matic 468_130)
    This episode also features News with Nancy Borman, Rebecca and Coca, "Sinsemella Street" with Yosemite Sam, and a poem by Vincent Titus.
  - Revolting Theatre, May 12, 1982; cuid29742 (Box 10, U-matic 468_131)
    60 minutes
  - Vincent Titus, Nancy Borman, Lannes Kenfield, Ponderosa Pine, May 19, 1982; cuid29743 (Box 10, U-matic 468_132)
  - Penguin Show, Steve Ben Israel walk off, Ivice singing, June 2, 1982; cuid29744 (Box 10, U-matic 468_133)
  - Freeze the Arms Race Show with Dave Dellinger, Meg Higgins, and the regulars, June 19, 1982; cuid29745 (Box 10, U-matic 468_134)
  - June 12th Rally with John Burke, John Schuchardt - Civil Disobedience Task Force, June 12, 1982; cuid29731 (Box 9, U-matic 468_118)
  - End of Season Finale with Christopher Robbins, Jim Buckley, June 30, 1982; cuid29732 (Box 9, U-matic 468_119)
  - "Yesterday's Donuts" Play, Broccoli by Clio Young, September 29, 1982; cuid29733 (Box 9, U-matic 468_120)
  - Paul Krassner, October 19, 1982; cuid29734 (Box 9, U-matic 468_121)
    Duration: 23 minutes. Preservation note: This tape required incubation, and the best possible capture was transferred.
  - Mainly Coca, with Vincent Titus and Lannes Kenfield, November 3, 1982; cuid29735 (Box 9, U-matic 468_122)
  - Alex Hershaft, Melinda Marks, Vincent Titus, Jim Buckley, Lannes Kenfield, Gus, November 23, 1982; cuid29746 (Box 10, U-matic 468_135)
    A note on the videotape says, "Especially cute part with Gus in the opening."
  - Rudi Harst, Laurence Cherniak, A poem from Vincent Titus, Nancy Borman and Rebecca, Bud Bogart, Lannes Kenfield, December 1, 1982; cuid30037C (Box 32, U-matic 468_455)